Discipline is a constant human awareness of the need
for action and a conscious act by us to
implement that action. Discipline is an awareness of
the constant need for action and a conscious
act to implement that action. If our awareness
and our implementations occur at the same time,
then we begin a valued sequence of disciplined
activity. Now, here's the other side of discipline.
If there's considerable time that passes between the
moment of awareness and the time of our
implementation, then that is called procrastination.
Procrastination, doing it tomorrow instead of
today. Procrastination, an almost exact opposite of
discipline. The voice within us says, get it
done. Discipline then says, do it now. Do it
to the best of your ability today, tomorrow, and always
until finally the worthy deed becomes
instinctive. Procrastination says later, tomorrow, whenever I
get a chance.
Do what is necessary to get by or to impress
others. Do what you can but not what you must.
Your nature moves you, and you never know when
your future will 문제 you, or when or what your
Finally we are veil backbone. конце are
not only executed, either by our metaphysical
personalities that tick mark them directly
or by our naturalث Handbook receivers that
Novi gandhard and Sharon Goyer are
now fully introduced into our informed skills.
Do it now or do it later,
discipline and procrastination. A choice between a
disciplined existence bearing the fruit
of achievement and contentment, or procrastination,
the easy life, pr which the future willеюсь you.
will bear no fruit, only the bare branches of mediocrity.
The rewards of a disciplined life are
great, but they're often delayed until sometime in
the future.
The rewards for the lack of discipline
are immediate, but they are minor in comparison
to the immeasurable rewards of consistent self-discipline.
An immediate reward for lack of discipline
is a fun day at the beach.
A future reward of discipline is owning the beach.
For most, we choose today's
pleasure rather than tomorrow's fortune.
So how can you get rid of the easy distractions?
How can you keep your mind
on what you're trying to do?
How can you keep an attitude of
doing it all and doing it now?
How can you make the
choice of discipline over procrastination?
How can you stay focused on your ambitions?
How can you avoid conversations at the water cooler?
You can keep your focus on your work.
You can get it done today instead of tomorrow.
You've got to really work on your
consistent self-discipline on a daily basis or you'll
find yourself distracted.
Distracted by negative thoughts, distracted by
negative people, distracted by water cooler
chatter.
And pretty soon, depending on the type
of people you've associated with, you'll be distracted.
And that's what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about the water cooler.
You want to keep your confidence.
But what's the point in keeping it for yourself?
That's what I want you to think about.
You don't need to be disappointed.
You want to be distracted by what
you're dealing with, distracted by your doubts within
yourself.
Never underestimate the power of influence and associations.
And never underestimate the power
of your own consistent self-discipline.
Now let's take a closer look at
discipline at the three steps to becoming disciplined.
First, true discipline is not the easiest option.
Most people would rather sleep until
10 o'clock then get up at 6.
Then you'll realize some of your thoughts around it.
It's easier to go to bed late,
sleep late, show up late, leave early.
It's easier not to read.
It's easier to turn on the
television than to open a book.
It's easier to do just
enough than to do it all.
Waiting is always easier than acting.
Trying is always easier than doing.
Imagine what life would be like if we didn't
have to make our bed in the morning or keep
our garage clean or pay our
taxes or show up for work tomorrow.
Wouldn't it be fascinating if we
didn't have to do these things?
Wouldn't it be fascinating?
What do you suppose would become of us?
You're right, not much.
For whatever the reason, the system we live
in and contribute to is designed to make the
easiest things in life the most unprofitable.
Profitable seems to be the most difficult.
Our world is...
And always will be a constant battle between
the life of ease and its momentary rewards
and a life of discipline
and its far more significant rewards.
Each has its own price.
The price of discipline or the price of regret.
We will pay one or the other.
What we wish we had done is the voice of
regret, speaking in a sorrowful tone at a time when
there is no going back.
This is regret.
No second chance.
No what would I do differently.
Choose one or the other, but both will
have their price, the price of discipline or the
price of regret.
One costs pennies, the other a fortune.
Dostoevsky said, there are hundreds of young men
who would die for the truth, but very
few who would spend five years in prison.
I'm not going to lie.
I'm wurdeating the truth, nor would I have
anything to do with the feeling that the true
act can be understood simply physically, in
order that they could choose either to move
forward or to stay onward.
You can go where you want and you
can go with what your принcesse really desire.
That's extremely important to all we
годуwts, that all honor could learn.
As I say, death is
a series ofнакl ihe ac kingdom.
To qualidade this reason, everybody on the earth
must know the true facts and the true
action in the question and in the question.
Death is the first lesson itself that we
hull have then in this life of greatroller Screw
death, If I say that, then what?
I'm nigh equal minded.
In truth it is.
activity. And we've said that the
best form of discipline is consistent self-discipline.
You see, the discipline that it takes to make
your bed every day is the same discipline necessary for
success in the world of business. The discipline
to organize your garage is the same discipline
to organize your business. All disciplines carry
through to affect all parts of our lives.
If we're disciplined in just one area and lazy
in another, guess what? Pretty soon the lazy side
will creep in and destroy the disciplined side. The
bad habits in one area of our life will
eventually destroy our self-discipline in the
areas we've been working on. Consistency cannot
be inconsistent. Discipline is the mind being
trained to control our lives. Discipline is a
set of steps that we take to make sure
we're disciplined in our lives. Discipline is the mind
being trained to control our lives. Discipline is
the mind being trained to control our lives.
We have the standards which we've
selected as a personal code of conduct.
Discipline is imposing on ourselves
the requirements for honoring these standards.
Once we've adopted these standards of behavior
and conduct, we're committed to honor them.
And if we don't, then there can
be no disciplined activity. We find ourselves
announcing our standards to our relatives, our
friends, our associates. We shout our beliefs
and condemn those who believe any differently, but then
we don't walk the talk. We end up acting
in a way far different from the beliefs we've
shouted. We tell our kids that the TV is rotting
their minds, yet we spend our evenings in front
of it. We tell our employees that they must take
advantage of every minute of the working day, yet
we spend three hours at lunch. Do as I say,
not as I do. This is inconsistent. Discipline
is the mind being trained to control our lives.
This leads to a loss of credibility among those
who watch us, and more importantly, this leads to
a loss of credibility within ourselves. The only
thing worse than one who is inconsistent in
applying their self-imposed disciplines is one who
has never considered the need or the value
of discipline at all. These people seem
to wander aimlessly changing procedures, changing standards,
changing laws, and changing our lives. But
the most important thing is that they're not
loyalties and shifting frequently from one
commitment to another, leaving behind a trail
of broken friendships, unfinished projects and
unfulfilled promises, all because of a
discipline that was either non-existent or
imposed so infrequently that it was ineffective.
Here's the third step
to becoming consistently self-disciplined.
Number one is realizing that
discipline isn't the easiest option.
Number two, discipline is a full-time
activity, day by day, every day.
And the third step to becoming self-disciplined is
really a philosophy that holds one of life's
unique promises.
Number three simply says for every
disciplined effort, there is a multiple reward.
That's one of life's great arrangements.
It's like the law of sowing and reaping.
In fact, it's an extension
of the law of the law.
It's an extension of the biblical law that
says if you sow well, you reap well.
Now here's a unique part of
the law of sowing and reaping.
Not only does it suggest that we'll all
reap what we've sown, it also suggests that we'll
reap much more.
Life is full of laws
that both govern and explain behaviors.
But this may well be the
major law we need to understand.
For every disciplined effort.
A multiple reward.
What a concept.
For every disciplined effort.
A multiple reward.
If you render unique service,
your reward will be multiplied.
If you're fair and honest and patient
with others, your reward will be multiplied.
If you give more than you expect to
receive, your reward is more than you expect.
But remember, the key word here,
as you might well imagine, is discipline.
Discipline.
Everything of value requires care and attention.
Everything of value requires discipline. Children
require discipline. They must have a structure
built for them. They must have boundaries to
work within so they feel secure and comfortable
to explore and grow. They must learn
to recognize what's right and what's wrong.
What's acceptable behavior, what's not
acceptable. Children require unwavering discipline, consistent
discipline or they'll be confused as
to how they're supposed to behave.
Likewise, our thoughts require discipline. We
must set up our inner boundaries,
our codes of conduct or our thoughts will be confused.
And with confused thoughts, we'll end up being confused,
hopelessly lost in the middle of the world.
It's just like a man who's lost his mind.
A maze of life. And
confused thoughts produce confused results.
Look around you at this very moment in
time. What might you be doing that needs attention?
Perhaps you're listening to this program as
you drive along in traffic, blowing your horn
at someone ahead of you who isn't driving
at the speed you'd like to. Perhaps you're listening
alone because you've had a disagreement with someone
you love or someone who loves you and your
anger is your own. You just haven't let go
of the thought of your holiness or your patience.
won't allow you to speak to that person, wouldn't this
be an ideal time to examine your need for a
new discipline? Perhaps you're on the brink of
giving up or starting over or starting out and
the only missing ingredient to your incredible success
story in the future is a new and
self-imposed discipline that will make you stay
longer and try harder and work more intensely
than you ever thought you possibly could. The
most valuable form of discipline is the one that
you impose on yourself. Don't wait for things
to deteriorate so drastically that someone else must
impose discipline into your life. Wouldn't that be
tragic? How could you possibly explain the fact
that someone else thought more of you than you
thought of yourself? That they forced you to get
up early and get out into the marketplace
when you were in the middle of the night?
Well even some people would have been content to let
success go to someone else who cared more about themselves cells
Your life, my life, the life of each one
of us is going to serve as either a warning
or an example. A warning of the consequences
of neglect, self-pity, lack of direction and ambition
or an example of talent
put to use, of discipline self-imposed
and of objectives clearlyomatized and
unquestionably tough for you butποhanded.
Your life of each one of us is going to serve as either a warning or an example a warning of the consequences of neglect self-pity
lack of direction and ambition or an example of talent put to use of discipline self-imposed and of objectives clearly Tik assesses clearly premeditated and unflinchingly outraged.
How then will tell if you're on the brink of giving up hope just because
of a need for another person and something that mighte help you not to succeed.
perceived and intensely pursued.